ABHIJEET KALE

Coventry, United Kingdom · +44 7721543425 abhi.kale123@gmail.com · LinkedIn · Portfolio

Result-oriented professional with 7 years of experience in Performance testing and engineering. Aiming to be an active part of a growth-oriented organization and to create a distinguished identity for myself through continuous learning and improvement.

EXPERIENCE

DEC 2022 - PRESENT

SENIOR PERFORMANCE TEST ENGINEER - TELUS HEALTH (FORMERLY LIFEWORKS)

- Setting up the Performance Testing Process in the organization.
- Understanding the product and provide performance testing solution.

AUG 2022 - DEC 2022

PERFORMANCE TEST SPECIALIST - IBM UNITED KINGDOM LIMITED

• Understanding and improving the performance testing process in one of the projects.

FEB 2021 – JUNE 2022

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER – TEST AUTOMATION – MEDIAOCEAN

- Understanding the product and analyzing the performance testing scope.
- Working with Management, Senior Architect to gather the requirements of the customer.
- Creating the reusable and maintainable performance testing script using Apache JMeter.
- For the execution purpose,
 - Integrating the JMeter scripts with Jenkins
 - Writing batch files to execute from the physical LG machines.
- Creating a detailed performance testing report on confluence page and sharing it with higher management.

SEPT 2018 - FEB 2021

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT – INFOSYS LIMITED

- Created a Performance testing solution for SAP GUI application with the help of automation tool and integrated it with BlazeMeter.
- Optimized the python code in order to make solution effective.
- Worked closely with development team of SAP Web Plugin to auto correlate dynamic values.
- Provided session within and outside organization on how to use SAP GUI and SAP Web solution.

• Point of Contact for all BlazeMeter architecture related questions, sessions and documentations within organization.

AUG 2017 -SEPT 2018

PERFORMANCE TEST ANALYST - ADROSONIC IT CONSULTANCY SERVICE PVT LTD

- Worked in Agile Methodology.
- Decided scope of NFT.
- Gathered requirements for performance testing.
- Created performance testing scripts using Apache JMeter.
- Installed agents in the server for monitoring.
- Handled execution and communication as a part of the project.
- Analysis of the test result.

DEC 2013 - MAY 2015

PROGRAMMER ANALYST - COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS

- Created performance testing scripts using LoadRunner.
- Created scenarios and perform executions on Performance Center and Controller.

EDUCATION

SEP 2017

M.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY COLLEGE DUBLIN

JUL 2013

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING ELECTRONICS AND TELECOMMUNICATIONS,

UNIVERSITY OF MUMBAI

SKILLS

- Apache JMeter, LoadRunner, BlazeMeter
- Python, Java, Groovy, SQL
- Web and Mobile Application Performance Testing
- Kibana, Solarwinds, Grafana, AppDynamics
 - AWS, Kubernetes
- Jenkins, Bitbucket/Git, Jira

AWARDS

- Outstanding Project Delivery Cognizant Technology Solutions.
- Certificate of Appreciation- Infosys Limited
- Tech/Domain Wizard Infosys Limited